In this lecture, I will give the introduction to JVM architectural TVM, that is Java Virtual Machine.
Joe Virtual Machine is responsible for executing Jallow program.
It provides the interpreter for execution of Chelo programs.
So let us take a real life example.
And Troadec, we will understand the requirements for running any program.
This is a seminar hall, not a hall or conference hall, or there is a magic show that has to be conducted
here.
Something has to be conducted here.
So does a big haul of eleven.
Great.
Let us take a real life example to understand how our program executes in the memory.
So here is a big hall as there are spaces there.
Let us assume deciles, memory loss has memory of our computer system.
There were programs executed on this hall.
As for conducting an insurer or a conference hall or a seminar hall or a magician is going to conduct
his show here.
So in this example, we will understand how a magician will utilize this entire space for conducting
his show.
And based on this observation.
We can easily understand how our program utilizes this memory.
So I will give the card details of this example.
So that same thing, we will be matching it with the program and the memory.
So let us talk about this example.
Suppose a magician is going to conduct a show here.
So he will reserve some someplace inside this hall for him, for himself.
He will have a stable cap there.
And the other tools or the objects that all he require for conducting a show.
So one portion of the room he will consume, then the rest of the place is for audience.
So how does the rest of the place is utilized for audience?
He will arrange some chairs.
So guess how many chiefs?
He will arrange as many tickets he has already sold.
Suppose he was marketing for this show for past one week or one month.
And he has sold about 50 tickets.
Then it means 50 audience are expected.
So he will arrange 50 chairs.
So before the even before the show, he already knows how many people are expected.
So that many space he will reserve for those people.
So he will provide that many chiefs.
Then there is a free area.
The CDI is free.
You can see that there's a free area, right?
Definitely.
There will be some free ADR available in these type of functions.
Why this?
The area is of a level building the show if anybody joins.
Then he can buy a ticket and he can come and sit here for him.
We need chairs.
There are no free chairs available.
So, yes, there is a heap of chairs available.
He can pick up he chairs from there and he can sit here in this area.
So this may happen during the execution of this show.
Right.
During the show.
So during the show, if somebody joins in.
He can sit here by taking a chair from he.
Again, I have repeated this point.
This is very important.
So finally, we can say that this entire hall is divided into three portions.
One portion is used by magician.
Right.
One portion is for the seating arrangement of the people who are already expected.
We know how many people are coming in and this area is used for those people who are joining during
the show.
Same Veve and a program runs into the main memory program required for utilizes the memory by dividing
into three sections, one section where the program resides.
Program itself a little aside like a magician stand.
That same thing is program itself because it's going to execute.
And it will be executed by the CBO.
It will be executed by the CBO.
Then whatever variables a program is having for them, it will look at the space in some memory area.
That area we call it does stack.
Then above dack free spaces there, and that space will be used.
But the optics at that aren't bad if the program is allocating memory are different time that memories
are limited from heap.
I will show you the details of this one in the next diagram.
Just let us move to the next diagram, the memory diagram.
I will give you all the details required for executing a program.
Think it as a general program, not just Java program.
Dovi, you're talking about Java program.
So I will be telling you those points that are common for programs of any language.
So let us study this diagram.
See, this is the memory given to the program for execution.
So already I have Mitry sections.
One is called Section Stack and Heap.
We will learn about it.
Now, this is a program, right?
This program, if you observe clearly, it is having three variables.
X, Y, Z.
This is supposed to be X, X mistake, Z is explicitly then three variables other than it is that friends
have friends is also a variable.
The new An object is created, object created.
And this is a literal.
This sum is literal because it is given in double quotes.
There's a little string little later on literalness.
Also, the constant object is also there because new is used and then three variables and one reference
or portal for variables that I like.
And the program is displaying something and for displaying something it is calling print and matured
or print.
Materne or Pendelton attacked.
Right.
So this what the program is doing and this is a Java program file here, compile this program.
It will get converted into bytecode and it will give a class file classified.
Now we will talk about execution.
All right, then.
You want to run the program.
Then this class file should come inside the main memory.
Then Walid can execute.
Yes.
It must come inside a mean memory.
Then only it can be executed by C.P.U.
Yes.
So this class file should be brought here.
So we call inside the main memory.
We call this process as loading.
We call it as loading does a loading process.
But in Java, everything is inside the glass.
Everything is in the in the form of classes.
So we we call deciles class loading.
We call the guest class loading.
So who will do this job in Java?
This is done by class loader.
So here I will write on.
This is a done by class loader which will bring this program that is in the form of a class inside the
main memory stored inside this mean memory.
It will store only met Hertz.
Right.
This class.
All these definitions are useless because actually matters are important.
So it will store this mean method.
Right.
It's all all the things inside.
Then this method is also using print.
So it will also store print matter.
It will also store in Matre does not present in our class.
The class name I have given as first.
But this is not partisan inside our class.
There's a first class right class first, then very present inside the system, not out.
So it should load tax system.
Class also means actually it will load, but intimate hurt.
So who does the job of bringing this bytecode inside the main memory for execution?
It is done by class.
That program should come here.
So who is a magician here?
The program itself is magician.
Yes, he is going to perform the show.
Then C.P.U will start executing the program.
Can see you understand bytecode.
No.
For that conversion of the school should be done in machine code.
So who will go back into Peter inside the job of a good act in DVM.
Right in interpreting and Jilian so interpreter.
Ah, there is one more thing.
That is Calise just didn't find compiler because interpreters are slower.
So Java uses again a compiler that is called as just in time compiler.
Vishy does the same thing, but it does it faster than interpret Catton.
All right.
So it will convert that gold into machine gold and get it executed by C.P.U.
That's mean Methode is having four variables X, Y, Z and Ostia, those variables will be created here
inside the stack X, Y, Z and SDR.
Then this main method is also having a string object created.
So this string object will be created here inside the heap.
Yes, it will be created inside heap.
And this will be a referee for this.
Yes.
So dynamic objects are created and said he never you see, in new every object is created in a heap.
Then local variables, normal variables and references.
And they will be inside the stack and they will be.
This will be belonging to mean method because this is there inside the meaning.
This is how normal variables are created inside stacked and objects.
When you say new, an object is created and that is kept inside heap.
The next inside the same program, you can see that print is also called Van Brinda Squalled and again,
its own STAC will be created.
So whatever the variables that are used inside the Sprint legacy, it is using some variable as something.
OK, we don't know what this metric this as unique as is used.
So those variables for local buy space in the start.
And if it is using the objects in the heap, it may be pointing to those objects or it may be creating
new objects.
Right.
So whatever it is happening inside and we are just assuming.
Either we're using the existing object or creating a new object.
But a new stack frame is created for this pend method also.
So it means whenever a metal discard, its stack frame is created.
That's it.
There are a lot of other things to study and understand in this mechanism, Manale.
So I don't want to go into detail.
This is sufficient for you to understand like.
So let us repeat the points that I have explained.
Class load.
I will bring the program from disk to mean memory.
Right.
This to me in memory.
And this ADR Vayle, the programs are kept is not called as code section.
This is Class Materne ADR in Java.
It is called as Mattel a.D.A.
Because it's not keeping the classes.
It's keeping just networks.
So this is class Materne.
a.D.A.
Who will do this job class loda.
Who will interpret the school and get it executed.
Interpreter or just in time compiler then vedova normal variables are created inside the stack and other
references are created inside the stack.
Then where the objects are created inside the heap.
I think one last point, that is where the liberals are kept, liberals are kept also inside the matured
area, or a section which is similar to a metro area, which we call the guys string poodle string pool.
So there will be part of metro area.
I already know what are the things that are required for executing the program so we can see the diagram
for the architecture of JVM.
So this is the diagram for Architectural Chivian.
It's not a detail like them.
We will be studying about detailed diagram.
But this diagram is containing all the components except some details.
OK.
So we will learn about these components.
See, I have discussable class that, you know, what does it do?
Yes.
Right.
Then this is a Jillian's memory.
You know that one portion of the memory where Matosi are kept, that is methode area.
Like I was calling it as code section.
This is the place where the magician stands, right.
His idea.
Then there's a stack.
So the local variables are the people who have already purchased tickets.
So the variables which are already there.
And we know that those make that much space basis required.
So those variables located in such tack.
And then this is Hape area.
Then this is for those people who are joining during the show, during the execution of the program,
during runtime.
So Davel, take the memory from Heap.
So that's what we call it as he picks up.
So these are the three sections which we have already studied.
Does the memory.
OK.
I will come to this.
But let us finish this one.
Also, execution engine.
Execution engine will have interpreter and just come git compiler.
We have already done about this.
I told you about this one.
This will our interpreter and git compiler interpreter will convert and execute every time.
But for some repeating code, Java or Jilian will quickly convert into machine code and repeatedly use
it.
That's for git compiler.
OK.
Will not translate every time.
Save Lydersen like a loop is there.
So that loop has to be repeated many times.
So all the statement inside loop will not be translated every time they can be converted to using git
compiler only for one time.
Then executed multiple times.
Right.
So interpreter or Jita compiler or whatever is required that Jiyeon will decide and use it.
And one more thing this JVM will contain.
That is called as garbage collector.
That is called as a garbage collector.
So this garbage collector will take away the objects from heap, whichever are not yours.
So just imagine that the people who joined the show during the show, they leave the show and during
the show itself and before the end of the show.
It may happen.
So if they are leaving, the chairs will be picked up by garbage collector.
So the objects that are created and heap will be collected away by a garbage collector.
So does the new thing.
We will learn more detail about garbage collector.
Then we have other things like C registered native methode stack and Netivot, an interface and native
method library.
Be seated, oestrus.
See, the addresses of the program will be kept inside the C.P.U for execution.
C.P.U will store their address or the next instruction to execute.
So here directly, C.P.U is not executing in between Jimmy and is in the wall.
So Jaivin will take it off.
Keeping the addresses of the next instruction to be executed and it will hand it over to you.
No doubt S.P. will execute, but Jovian will also interfere in the execution process.
The reason is it is responsible for it.
So it more than one registers maybe there.
So Chivian will take care of it.
Now, lastly, in Java, we can also invoke or call the networks of other languages like C and C++.
So Dachis called us net native Mattocks, the Materne.
So we charted and in C and C++ are called S Native Materne because they are black farm dependent.
So if those matters are called in, they will be a separate stock for them.
An interface for Java program to native Matt Hertz.
So that's why Native Method Interface and in plus was also we have the library and title library.
Matre Library is available.
So this is about native Materne.
So this you can treat it as external.
Not a part of Java program.
Also Java program.
But JVM is responsible for that.
So it is there inside you.
So that's it.
I have covered all the components.
Now we will learn about the details of these components.
Next lecture, I will discuss this topic in detail once again.
So that's all in this video.